# **VI Long Tran**

#### **DevOps Engineer**

#### **Profile**

DevOps Engineer with 2+ years of experience working in various technology fields including CI/CD, Microservices, and Embedded application developments. Skilled in developing platforms to support implementing and maintaining CI/CD pipelines, developing and deploying Microservices as containerization in the Kubernetes clusters.

## **Education**

## Ho Chi Minh University of Technology

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam Aug 2018 - Sep 2022

Falcuty of Computer Science of Engineering

Bachenlor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

## **Licenses & Certifications**

- Ets TOEIC for Reading-Listening skills with 640/990 scores. (Aug. 2022)
- Ets TOEIC for Speaking-Writing skills with 200/400 scores. (Sep. 2022)
- Fundamentals of Action Learning from WIAL Vietnam. (Oct. 2023)

# **Experience**

### **DEK Technologies Vietnam**

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

DevOps Engineer

Feb 2022 - Present

- CI/CD Pipeline Management: Creation and maintenance of the Argo Workflow pipeline, streamlining development processes for enhanced efficiency.
- Automation Expertise: Utilize scripts and Python, in conjunction with Docker, Kubernetes, Helm, and Jfrog Artifactory, to automate tasks seamlessly through the Argo Workflow CI pipeline.
- **Deployment Management**: Proficiently work with **Argo CD** to deliver resources to designated locations, ensuring a smooth deployment process.
- o Clusters management: Use Rancher for effectively manage Kubernetes clusters.
- o Unit Testing: Employ Python and Pytest to write comprehensive unit test cases for Microservices developed using Python.
- Backend deveploment: Develop Microservices nodes using Python that provide RESTful APIs to support for CI/CD pipelines.
- Task Management: Efficiently manage daily tasks through Jira and follow Agile way of working, ensuring seamless coordination and prioritization.
- o **Collaborative Problem Resolution**: Proactively bring up ideas, and engage in discussions with team members to identify and resolve challenges.

# CloudNine: The Automation Software Company

Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam Jun 2021 - September 2021

Embedded Linux Intern

- **Unittest implementation**: Write unit test cases for C++ application using **CppTest** framework.
- **GNU Make**: Write Makefile for compiling C++ application on Linux environment.

# Other Projects

- Flashcard tracker: An application built from Python and deployed in AWS ECS that communicates with users in Telegram, helps to learn and remember vocabulary performed in Flashcard.
- O **Health and life service**: Service built from Python and deployed in AWS ECS reminds users about goals in the day and scheduler via WhatsApp.
- O **Autonomous robot in uncertain environments**: Autonomous robot has model Turtlebot3 burger that can determine obstacles and move throughout open points to go to goal.

# Skills

- **Programming Languages:** C, C++, Python, Bash
- Technologies: AWS, Kubernetes, Docker, Helm, Rancher, Argo Workflows, Argo CD, Artifactory, Git
- Developing environments: Linux, Windows
- Database: MySQL, Microsoft SQL, Elasticsearch
- Data visualization: Kibana, Matplotlib
- Communication Protocol: RESTful API, MQTT, Kafka
- Soft Skills: Presentation, Planning, Organized, Creative Problem-Solving, Teamwork, Active Listening, Adaptability

# Languages

• Vietnamese [Native]

• English [Intermediate] - B2++